ssfcu.org 2001-12-05

# Privacy Policy - Security Service Federal Credit Union

| 

---|---  
  
##### How Security Service Federal Credit Union Protects your Privacy

At Security Service Federal Credit Union, your privacy is a top priority.  Because you trust us with your financial and other personal information, we are committed to respect your privacy and safeguard that information.  This notice describes how we protect that privacy of your personal information and gives you an opportunity to let us know if you do not want us to share your information with some of our business partners. 

This privacy policy explains:

Ø       **How we protect your information when you visit the Security Service Federal Credit Union Website, and **

Ø **Security Service Federal Credit Union’s own Privacy Policy to safeguard your information.**

**INTERNET PRIVACY**

**Q. Is my privacy protected if I visit Security Service Federal Credit Union’s Website ([www.ssfcu.org](http://www.ssfcu.org/)) on the Internet?**  
---  
  
**A. Yes.** As a visitor to our Website, you need not be concerned about the privacy of your personal information. For your protection, the credit union uses a process called “encryption” to secure your on-line banking sessions. Encryption turns all Internet communications between you and the credit union – from your passwords to your money transfer requests – into a string of unrecognizable numbers. Only the credit union and our authorized business partners can decode this information. This process safeguards your on-line banking sessions from intruders.  In addition, when simply browsing the Security Service Federal Credit Union’s Website, our Web server recognizes only:

  * Your Internet Service Provider (for example, America Online or Earthlink), but not your specific e-mail address.  For instance, if your  e-mail address is “johndoe@earthlink.net,” only the earthlink.net part of the address is recognized by our system.    

  * Aggregate information about the pages that our members visit. However, no information on pages visited by any individual member is retained.  The aggregate information we collect (for instance, how many “hits” we receive on a particular Web page) is included for internal review so that we may improve the content of our Web page.  This information is later discarded.

**Q. Does Security Service Federal Credit Union collect online information about me?**  
**A. Yes, but only if you voluntarily provide us with your information.** We obtain information such as your e-mail address, mailing address and telephone number only if you provide the information to us. Like all other information you provide to the credit union, our policy on sharing this information applies to online transactions.  Here’s what we do with information volunteered by you as a member and visitor to [www.ssfcu.org:](http://www.ssfcu.org/)  

**a.    ****E-Mail Address-** If you supply us with your e-mail address on-line, you will only receive the information that you requested when you provided us with your e-mail address. 

**b.       ****Mail Address-** If you supply us with your mailing address on-line, you will only receive the information that you requested when you provided your address.

**c.       ****Telephone Number-** If you supply us with your telephone number on-line, you will receive telephone contact from us only for the purpose of providing you with information regarding your on-line request.

**d.       ****Cookies** \- A cookie is a piece of data that a Website can send to your browser, which is then stored on your computer.  Currently, SSFCU does not save cookies on our Website.  However, based on future applications and/or membership needs, SSFCU reserves the right to use cookies on its Website.  At such time a change occurs, SSFCU will clearly disclose the use of cookies on the Website.  SSFCU cooperates with third parties to allow products and services to be made available to our members.  Upon leaving the SSFCU Website and entering the Website of a third party you may be served with a cookie.     
  
**Q. Does Security Service Federal Credit Union allow me to submit loan applications on-line?  **  
**A. Yes.** Our on-line applications assist us in quickly processing your loan request.  The disclosure of information is entirely voluntary on your part and, if you choose to give it, the personally identifying data will be used both to make our loan decision as well as provide you with additional information about our credit union and the products and services we offer.  However, if you choose not to give us the  complete information we request in our application, we may not be able to process your loan request.     
  
**SECURITY SERVICE FEDERAL CREDIT UNION PRIVACY POLICY   **

Concern for member confidentiality and privacy has been a hallmark of Security Service Federal Credit Union operations for decades.  At Security Service Federal Credit Union, our employees treat the information we have concerning your accounts in the same responsible, confidential way that we want our own financial affairs treated.  We think it’s important for you, our member, to be informed of the policies we have in place to safeguard your privacy.

We do all that we can to make sure that any information we have about our members is accurate, and is reviewed only by those employees to either provide services to you, or need to know the information in order to carry out credit union business.   

Other than the limited exceptions explained in this policy, it is our practice not to share confidential member information with anyone outside of the Security Service Federal Credit Union and our family of companies.  You do not need to request this confidentiality – it is our standard practice.

We educate our employees about their responsibility to protect your privacy.  We also maintain physical, electronic, and procedural safeguards to ensure your information remains protected.

Here are answers to some of the questions you may have about our policy:  

**Q. What information does Security Service Federal Credit Union collect about me?  **  
---  
  
**A. The information we collect about our members is used only for legitimate business purposes.**   This information may include data about your identity (such as your name, address, social security or driver’s license number), your transactions with Security Service Federal Credit Union and its CUSO (such as your account number, loan or account balance), and your credit report or similar information (such as information about your credit standing or other characteristics) obtained from credit bureaus and other sources outside of Security Service Federal Credit Union.  
  
**Q. To what extent does Security Service Federal Credit Union share this information with others?  **  
  
**A. Security Service Federal Credit Union does not disclose any nonpublic personal information about our members or former members to anyone, except as permitted by law.**   Like virtually all other financial institutions, we lawfully share information when it is necessary to provide you services such as data processing, check printing, insurance products as well as to companies that perform marketing services on our behalf or to other financial institutions with whom we have joint marketing agreements. These vendors are required to treat such member information confidential and use the information only for the specific credit union purpose stated. In fact, our Vendors are specifically prohibited from reusing, disclosing or selling your information.  
  
**Q. What is the Security Service Federal Credit Union CUSO?  **  
**A. Security Service Federal Credit Union CUSO is a sister company   of Security Service Federal Credit Union, owned exclusively by us, for the purpose of providing services to our members. **In other words, our CUSO is an affiliated company of the credit union that expands the types of services that we can offer to you. The law permits us to share information between the credit union and our CUSO.  However you may direct us not to share certain types of    information within our family of companies such as information obtained from a consumer report, credit score or your credit history, information provided by you on a credit application, as well as similar information obtained from others. If you wish to be excluded from sharing this information between the Security Service Federal Credit     Union family, please write to Security Service Federal Credit Union, P.O. Box 691510, San Antonio, Texas 78256 or you may call 1-800-52-SSFCU (800-527-7328).
